American Vaudeville Museum collection, 1850s-2007 (bulk 1910s-1940s)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
American Vaudeville Museum collection 1845-2007 (bulk 1910-1940)
MS 421
Cullen, Frank, 1936-?, McNeilly, Donald, 1945-, American Museum of Vaudeville
This collection consists of materials documenting vaudeville and other entertainment in the United States, particularly in the 1910s through 1940s. Primary materials such as photographs, scrapbooks and handwritten stage scripts document the careers of particular performers. There are substantial numbers of sheet music and theatre programs, and a large LP collection. The collection focuses on vaudeville but encompasses other forms and eras of American entertainment as well.
66.8 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Notes on Collection Access
Many of the items in this collection are extremely fragile and therefore not available for handling. For the scrapbooks in particular, reference photocopies have been provided for viewing.
Patrons must use motion picture reels under the direct supervision of the Manuscripts Librarian. Preservation copies of this material are not currently available. Depending upon equipment availability and item condition, users may not be able to view this material.
Historical Note
This archive was collected by Frank Cullen and Donald McNeilly, founders of the American Museum of Vaudeville (commonly referred to as the American Vaudeville Museum) in Boston. Many of the materials pertain to the Boston and New York areas. Some items were purchased by Cullen and McNeilly; others were contributed by fans and other interested persons, or by family members of performers from the vaudeville era. Many of the histories gathered by Cullen and McNeilly were published in their periodical, The Vaudeville Times. The culmination of their research appeared in their two-volume encyclopedia, Vaudeville Old & New, co-authored also by Florence Hackman. The collection was donated by the Museum in 2008.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 32 series:
Series I: Vaudeville Reference Materials, ca. 1897-2007
Series II: Promotional Materials, 1990-2006
Series III: Thematic Subjects
Series IV: Performers
Series V: Obituaries
Series VI: Theatres, 1892-2007
Subseries 1: Theatre Postcards, Photographs and Ephemera, ca. 1894-2004
Subseries 2: Theatre Programs, 1892-2007
Subseries 3: Souvenir Programs, 1899-1999
Subseries 4: Boston Theatre Programs, ca. 1920-1945
Series VII: Photographs, 1906-1961
Series VIII: Posters and Oversize Items, ca. 1850s-1980s
Series IX: Sheet Music, 1859-1945 (bulk 1905-1935)
Series X: Periodicals, 1894-2007
Series XI: Balasic Family Collection, 1904-1930, 1990s
Series XII: Dixon-Freeman Collection, 1864, 1919-1935
Series XIII: Cato Sells Keith Collection, ca. 1911-1928
Series XIV: Kill Kare Kouple Collection, ca. 1890-1933
Series XV: Olsen and Johnson Collection, ca. 1941-1949, 1995-2002
Series XVI: Sonia Serova Collection, ca. 1917-1925
Series XVII: Doreen Rae Collection, ca. 1919-1931
Series XVIII: Gondoliers-Ricci Collection, 1933-1936
Series XIX: Rooney Collection, ca. 1892-2006 (bulk ca. 1910-1940s)
Series XX: Frank J. Sidney Collection, ca. 1900-1965 (bulk ca. 1900-1928)
Series XXI: Leon Errol Collection, 1904-1940s
Series XXII: Belle Story Collection, ca. 1914-1920
Series XXIII: McWatters-Tyson Collection, ca. 1898-1936 (bulk 1910s-ca. 1925)
Series XXIV: Willie, West & McGinty Collection, ca. 1930s
Series XXV: Paul Gerard Smith Collection, ca. 1918-1960, ca. 2000-2001
Series XXVI: Fan Scrapbook Collection, ca. 1897-1914, ca. 1930-1935
Series XXVII: Films, ca. 1930-1947
Series XXVIII: Media, ca. 2000-2007
Series XXIX: Commemoratives, undated
Series XXX: Hippodrome Theatre Actors' Accessories, ca. 1910s
Series XXXI: Performance Costumes, undated
Series XXXII: LP Record Collection, American Vaudeville Museum
Subseries 1: LP records: Blues, Revue, Jazz, and Cabaret - Solo Singers
Subseries 2: LP records: Blues, Revue, Jazz, and Cabaret - Compilations
Subseries 3: LP records: British Music Hall and Revue - Solo or Small Revue
Subseries 4: LP records: British Music Hall and Variety - Compilation Albums
Subseries 5: LP Records: Vaudeville and Early Film Musicals Singers - Compilations
Subseries 6: LP Records: American Vaudeville Performers - Comedians Solo or Duo
Subseries 7: LP Records: American Vaudeville Performers - Singers Solo or Duo
Subseries 8: LP Records: American Vaudeville Performers - Compilations
Subseries 9: LP Records: Broadway Musicals
Subseries 10: LP Records: Hollywood Musicals
Subseries 11: LP Records: Spoken Word Recordings - Classic Actors
Subseries 12: LP Records: Spoken Word Recordings - Miscellany
Subseries 13: LP Records: Spoken Word Recordings - Comedians, Solo or Teams
Subseries 14: LP Records: Folk Music - Solo Singers or Family Acts
Subseries 15: LP Records: Folk Music - Compilations
Subseries 16: LP Records: Instrumentalists - Blues (mostly solos) and Jazz (mostly small combos)
Subseries 17: LP Records: Instrumentalists - Blues (mostly solos) and Jazz (combos)
Subseries 18: LP Records: Instrumentalists - Blues and Early Jazz - Compilations (mostly piano)
Scope and Content Note
This collection, originally located at the American Vaudeville Museum in Boston, comprises theatre programs and postcards, sheet music, magazines, playbills, photographs and posters, stage scripts and other manuscripts, clippings and scrapbooks, films, miscellaneous papers, and a large collection of LP albums, as well as some entertainers' costumes and accessories. Some materials are included as photocopies rather than in original form. There are primary materials such as scrapbooks and handwritten stage scripts that document the careers of particular performers, often couples or family members. The collection focuses on vaudeville but encompasses other forms and eras of American entertainment as well, such as film and recorded music.
Specific descriptions of scope and content are provided for each series, along with biographical notes for the individual performers' collections.
Access Terms
Clinton, Julia Rooney
Clinton, Walter
Dixon, Jessica
Errol, Leon, 1881-1951
Freeman, Frank
Johnson, Chic, 1891-1962
Keith, Cato Sells
McNeilly, Donald, 1945-
McWatters, Arthur J.
Olsen, Ole, 1892-1963
Rae, Doreen
Rooney, Pat, 1880-1962
Rooney, Pat, 1926-
Serova, Sonia
Sidney, Frank J.
Smith, Paul Gerard, 1894-1968
Story, Belle
Tyson, Grace
Wright, Chester A.
B.F. Keith (firm)
Orpheum Circuit, Inc.
Pantages Circuit of Vaudeville Theatres
Radio-Keith-Orpheum Corporation
American Museum of Vaudeville
American Vaudeville Museum
Blackface entertainers
Burlesque (Theater)
Entertainers -- United States
Minstrel shows
Musical theater
Theaters -- United States
Cullen, Frank, 1936-
McNeilly, Donald
American Museum of Vaudeville
Manuscripts
Photographs
Black and white photographs
Posters
Scrapbooks
Sheet music
Sound recordings
Motion pictures
Related Material
See also the David Soren Popular Sheet Music Collection, MS 365.
Linda Diane Jackson Collection, MS 457
Bibliography
A publication related to this archive, and reproducing many of the items included in it, is
Vaudeville Old & New: An encyclopedia of variety performers in America, by Frank Cullen, with Florence Hackman and Donald McNeilly (New York: Routledge, 2007), in 2 volumes.
Related articles may also be found in
The Vaudeville Times, 40 issues of which were published by The American Museum of Vaudeville from spring 1998 to Winter 2007.
Container List
- Series I: Vaudeville Reference Materials, ca. 1897-2007, 1 linear foot
  Scope and Content
  This series includes photocopies and printouts from various sources, as well as loose original articles and other texts.
  - "Black women recording pioneers," by Rainer Lotz. IAJRC Journal, vol. 40, no. 2 ( May 2007), pp. 32-41 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Boston Opera House (Keith Memorial Theatre) - articles from the Boston Sunday Globe, 2004 (photocopies) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    "Virtually Vaudeville," June 20, 2004
    "Another opening, another show," June 27, 2004
  - Boston Theatre District (map - former streets, demolished historic buildings, former theatres, etc.) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Cabaret comeback," by Elizabeth Kendall. Civilization, Feb.-Mar. 1999, pp. 34-36 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Comedy shorts - typed list (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cosmopolitan, 1897?-1905 - articles (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Actress aided by camera," by Daniel Frohman. Cosmopolitan, Feb. 1897?, pp. 413-420.
    - "Where vaudeville holds the boards," by Charles R. Sherlock; "The postal-card craze," by Julian Ralph. Cosmopolitan, Feb. 1902, pp. 411-426
    - "The future of vaudeville in America," by Israel Zangwill. Cosmopolitan 38 Apr. 1905, pp. 639-646 (2 copies)
  - Chinese performance art (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - "Chinese Vaudeville: Xiangsheng and the Performer Hou Baolin" by Shu-ying Tsau, May-June 1979, for "Workshop on Contemporary Chinese Literature and the Performing Arts", Harvard, June 1979
    - Report by Frank Cullen on researching Chinese performance art in English language holdings at Harvard Yenching Library, June 6, 1996
  - Down Memory Lane, by Guy Magley, n.d. - booklet with names of vaudeville acts listed by city and theatre, 1914-15, 1926, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "The evolution of American vaudeville," by John J. Murdock (source not identified) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Keith/Albee Collection (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Keith/Albee Collection Inventory, University of Iowa Libraries
    - "The Keith/Albee Collection: The vaudeville industry, 1894-1935" by M. Alison Kibler, Books at Iowa 56, Apr. 1992
  - "In Vaudeville" by Hartley Davis, Everybody's Magazine, Aug. 19, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Jugglers, past and present" by M.S. Mahendra, Linking Ring, Dec. 1944 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Lest We Forget": Curtain falls on notable theatrical personages in 1949 (13th ed.); 1950 (14th ed.); 1951 (15th ed.). From the records compiled by Paul E. Glase, Fabian's Embassy Theatre, Reading, Pa. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Library of Congress, 1993-1995, Correspondence between Frank Cullen and LC reference librarian Madeline F. Matz, 1993-1995, and printout search results, for LC holdings of early silent films related to vaudeville, Vitaphone short films, and films with all-black casts. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - [List of theaters and contact information], ca. 2000 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Memphis Vaudeville Theater Orchestras" by Roy C. Brewer, from diss. Professional Musicians in Memphis, Tennessee (1900-1950) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - The Mississippi Rag, 2004 - articles (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - "Sax appeal," by William J. Schafer, Oct. 2004, pp. 32-33, "The TJEN corner," by Dave Robinson, founder, Traditional Jazz Educators Network, Oct. 2004, p. 34; - review of books and recordings about the Six Brown Brothers
  - "New York Theatres 1882 to 1939, Now Demolished" - typed list (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "The Origin, Development, and Significance of Dramatic Entertainment in American Vaudeville, 1893-1925," by Mari Lyn Henry (thesis, Catholic University of America, 1968) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "Notes on the Principal Spanish Dances," by Vicente Escudero (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Orpheum Circuit (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Orpheum Circuit of Theatres, 1909 - booklet, published upon the occasion of the dedication of the New Orpheum Theatre, San Francisco
    - "The Orpheum Road Show," 1908 - photograph of flyer
    - "Origin of Orpheum Circuit," by Epes W. Sargent, July 24, 1934
  - Orpheum Theatres (San Francisco, Calif.) - correspondence, papers, photocopies (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "The Palace" by Donald Wayne ( Holiday, March 1951, pp. 63-66+)- photocopy, lacks first page; accompanied by typed text and summary (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Panning the 'pan' time: being a compilation of information appertaining to the Pantages Circuit," "cooked up" by Herbert Lloyd, "chef de claque", 1917 - booklet (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Paramount turns 75: Oldest U.S. movie studio proves to be survivor," by Joseph Gelmis; Cape Cod Times, Jul 10, 1987, p. 24 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Performance arts bibliography, 1995 (source not identified) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Play Production, by Henning Nelms, 1950 - photocopy (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Poster catalogs (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Christie's - Hollywood Posters, Christie's East, Tuesday, Dec. 11, 1990
    - Sports Movie Posters,, vol. 4 of The Illustrated History of Movies Through Posters, comp. Richard Allen and Bruce Hershenson, 1996
  - "Primary Sources in Vaudeville History: A Survey," by Michael Leininger, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Telemedia Soundies" and Telemedia catalog (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Theatre articles, various - photocopies (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - "Historic Uptown may get an encore at last," Chicago Sun Times, Dec. 1, 2006
    - "A palace of a playhouse: Rockford's Coronado Theatre," Historic Illinois, Aug. 2001
    - "The rise and fall of the Old Howard," Boston Sunday Globe, May 20, 2001
    - "Vaudeville once again takes center stage at Netcong theater," Star-Ledger, Sep. 12, 2003
  - "They Stopped the Show" 1969 - album cover and liner notes (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "To Artists" by E.F. Albee (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - T.O.B.A. (Theater Owners Bookers Association; black vaudeville) - photocopies (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Vitaphone Project, Vitaphone News, vol. 1 (fall 1991), vol. 2 (undated), vol. 4, no. 1 (summer 1998), vol. 4, no. 2 (fall 1998)- web page printouts (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - The White Rats (actors' union) (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - "A historical study of the White Rats of America," by Thomas Colley (thesis, Wayne State University, 1967)
    - The Player, Dec. 22, 1916 - photocopy
    - E.A. Albee, The Dromio, The Original Eight - digital prints
  - "Yesterday's movie stars in their heaven on earth," by Bill Slocum, Record American, Feb. 5-6, 1971, re: Motion Picture Country House and Hospital (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Series II: Promotional Materials and Business Materials, ca. 1997-2006, .25 linear foot
  This series consists of brochures, correspondence, and other promotional materials from organizations. There is also a series of periodicals, Lambs Script, provided by their issuing organization. The series is arranged alphabetically by organization.
  - American Southwestern Railway Association (Los Angeles, Calif.) - correspondence, "The Little Nugget" promotional card, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - American Vaudeville Theatre (Brooklyn, NY) - brochure, after 1996 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Audio Film Center - brochure pages (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - British Music Hall Society, Players Theatre (London, England) - correspondence and information, 1998-2000 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Certificates of Authenticity undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Frank Cullen / Vaudeville Museum undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Frank Cullen / Turner Entertainment undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Harvard Theatre Collection (Cambridge, Mass.) (Box 3, Folder 8)
    "Cross-Dressing in the Theatre" - lecture/exhibition announcement, 2003
    "Dime Museums and Nickel Theatres" - exhibition brochure, 2006
  - The Institute of the American Musical (Los Angeles, Calif.) - press kit, ca. 1998 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - The International Al Jolson Society ( Norman Conrad) - order form, correspondence (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - KiMo Theatre (Albuquerque, N.M.) - folder, flyers; incl. Spencer Theater for the Performing Arts (Ruidoso/Alto, N.M.) flyer (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - The Lambs (New York, N.Y.) - correspondence, "Installation Gambol" dinner program, 1998; Lambs Script, Jan/Feb 1997 - spring 1998 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Moschen, Michael ( David Belenzon Management, Inc.) - press kit, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Museum of the Moving Image, British Film Institute (London, England) - correspondence and flyers, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - National Comedy Hall of Fame (St. Petersburg, Fla.) - press kit, ca. 1997 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - New York Friar's Club (New York, N.Y.) - booklet, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - New York Public Library for the Performing Arts (New York, N.Y.) - exhibition brochure, "Vaudeville Nation," 2005-2006 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Palm Springs Follies (Palm Springs, Calif.) - press kit, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Periwinkle Entertainment Productions (Anaheim, Calif.) - press kit, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - University of Southern California (Los Angeles, Calif.), Donehy Memorial Library - exhibition booklet, "Setting the State: The Rise of American Popular Theater" 2005 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Series III: Thematic Subjects, .5 linear foot
  This series comprises photographs, articles, stamps, postcards, and photocopies that were organized by the American Vaudeville Museum based on themes rather than performers. The holdings in this series are generally minimal, with only one or a few items in each category.
  - Acrobats, Balancing Acts, Bicycle Acts (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Harry Decoe
    Rice and Prevost
    Kay Farrelli, Holiday on Ice, 1950s-1960s?
    Mel Hall, and The Fabulous Cycling Whiz Kids (Mel Hall's Kids)
    Bobby May
    The Percelly's, Holiday on Ice, 1955
    Rice & Prevost
    Eddy Rose and Marion
    Harry Sykes
    Tubby & Spats
    Jimmy Valdare & Duffy
    "Where Vaudeville Holds the Boards," by Charles R. Sherlock; Cosmopolitan, Feb. 1902
  - Acts Who Used Drawings (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - African Americans (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Sandy Burns
    Dixie Strutters
    Radcliffe and Rogers
  - Burlesque (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Four Sisters Ruby
    Helen Leach, Wallin Trio
  - Caricatures and Drawings, (Subjects of drawings include Dardanelle, Anita O'Day, Walter Lippman, Bessie Smith, and Maxine Sullivan. Two are part of a card series, Women Singers of Cafe Society.) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Caricatures and drawings by Frank Cullen
    "The Algonquin Wits", caricature by Hirschfield, The New York Times Book Review, May 19, 1968
    Caricatures of celebrities, 1927 - Cocoanut Grove, by Ralph Barton, and 1996 - Mortons, by David Cowles, Vanity Fair
  - Clowns (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Dance Acts (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Maarya and Rene Gunsett
    Al and Carmelita Hernandez
  - Entrepreneurs (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Michael O'Harro, Champions stuff cards, ca. 2001
  - Flash Act; posters (color reproductions) (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Gavine and Arnette
    T.F. Harris
    A. Mae Preston
    Washer Brothers, "Champion Scientific Midget Boxers"
    Weston and Beasley
  - Little People (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Bob Hermine's Magazine of Midgets, 1945
    The Doll Family (Tiny, Harry, Daisy, Grace)
    Hansel and Gretel
    King and Prince
    Royal Lilliputians
  - Movies: promotional photos - "Brother, Can You Spare a Dime" (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Movies: promotional photos - "The Great American Broadcast" (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Movies: promotional photos - various (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Airplane
    Alien
    All Quiet on the Western Front
    The Apartment ( Jack Lemmon, Shirley MacLaine)
    Bob & Carol & Ted & Alice
    Butterfly ( Stacy Keach, Pia Zadora)
    The Chinese Connection ( Bruce Lee)
    The Conspirators ( Hedy Lamarr and Paul Henreid)
    Elephant Man
    From Russia with Love ( Sean Connery)
    Gold Rush Maisie
    The Great American Broadcast
    Hardcore ( George C. Scott)
    Hercules Unchained ( Steve Reeves)
    High Plains Drifter ( Clint Eastwood)
    Incredible Shrinking Woman ( Lily Tomlin)
    The Late Show ( Lily Tomlin)
    My Life with Caroline ( Ronald Colman and Anna Lee)
    A Night at Earl Carroll's ( Jack Norton)
    The Night the Lights Went Out in Georgia
    Nobody's Perfekt ( Gabe Kaplan, Alex Karras, Robert Klein)
    Only When I Laugh ( Kristy McNichol and Marsha Mason)
    Parachute Battalion ( Harry Carey, Buddy Ebsen, Richard Cromwell, Edmond O'Brien, Robert Preston)
    The Perils of Pauline
    Pixote
    Play Girl
    Pollyanna ( Hayley Mills)
    Richard Pryor: Here and Now
    Scanty Panties ( Virginia Bell, Irving Benson, Max Furman, Billy "Cheese & Crackers" Hagan)
    Star Wars
    Strange Idols ( Dustin Farnum)
    Sunny
    Tarzan ( Johnny Weissmuller)
    Tommy
    Walking My Baby Back Home ( Donald O'Connor)
    What's New Pussycat
    Zorro, the Gay Blade ( George Hamilton)
    Unidentified
  - Movies: "Polyester" (Odorama) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Movies: "Rize" (review) (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Musicians (Box 4, Folder 16)
    International Cornet School, Inc. (Boston, Mass.) - pupil lesson receipt card
    Musicians Supply Co. (Boston, Mass.) - catalog, 1920s
  - Player/Actor Bios (Box 4, Folder 17)
    "Mrs. Wiggs in the Cabbage Patch" by Ethyl Eichelberger
  - Postcards (Box 4, Folder 18)
    To Lilly Chargé of Magdeburg, 1900-1908
    To Julia Redman of Brooklyn and Long Island, 1910-1914
  - Singers, misc. ( Mildred Bailey, Rosemary Clooney, Ethel Waters) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Stamps (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Tap dance (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Postcards of performances in Germany, 2002-2005
    Urban Tap (Boston, Mass.), founder/performer Herbin "Tamango" Van Cayseele
  - Vaudeville acts (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Ventriloquists (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Vitaphone - photographs (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Crystal Cave Revue
    Xavier Cugat and His Gigolos
    Florentine Choir
    The Ingenues
    Morrisey & Miller Revue
    Jesse Stafford Orchestra
    Earnie Stanton
- Series IV: Performers, 4.75 linear foot
  This series consists of clippings, photographs, announcements, sheet music, publications, and ephemera. The subjects are individual and group performers; they include singers, dancers, female impersonators, acrobats, jugglers, actors, clowns and comedians. It is organized alphabetically - by performer's surname, by stage name, or by group name - with oversize material grouped at the end.
  Two more substantial collections originally received among this material - Frank J. Sidney and Doreen Rae - have been organized separately.
  - Performers A - Be
    - Abbott and Costello ( Bud Abbott and Lou Costello) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Abeles, Edward (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Adams, Maude (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Adams, S.S. ( Samuel Sorenson Adams) (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Ailey, Alvin (dance company) (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Albee, Edward Franklin (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Allan, Maud (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Allard, Bee (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Anderson, Eddie "Rochester" (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Anderson, Ernestine (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Andrews Sisters ( Laverne Andrews; Patty Andrews; Maxene Andrews) (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Arden, Eve (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Arnaz, Desi (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Ashcroft, Peggy (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Ashford, Pauline (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Avner the Eccentric ( Avner Eisenberg) (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Baez, Joan (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Baker, Josephine (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Ball, Lucille (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Bankhead, Tallulah (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Bara, Theda (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Barnet, Robert A. (producer), and Eltinge, Julian (female impersonators) (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Barrymore, Ethel (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - El Barto ( James Barton, 1858-1935) (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Barton, James, 1890-1962 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Barty, Billy (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Bates, Peg Leg ( Clayton Bates) (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Bayes, Nora (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Bennett, Richard (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Benny, Jack (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Bentley, Gladys (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Bergen, Edgar (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Bergman, Ingrid, and Matthau, Walter (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Berle, Milton (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Bernie, Ben (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Bernhardt, Sarah (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Performers Bi - Bu
    - Bigger, Laura (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Bindlestiff Family Cirkus (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Bizzarro Brothers (Box 6, Folder 3)